<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure Functions on Sander Rozemuller | All about Automation, Monitoring for Identity, AVD and Intune</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/azure-functions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure Functions on Sander Rozemuller | All about Automation, Monitoring for Identity, AVD and Intune</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 09:12:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/azure-functions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Monitor Intune using Azure Functions, PowerShell, Graph API and MS Teams</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/monitor-intune-using-azure-functions-powershell-and-graph-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 09:12:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/monitor-intune-using-azure-functions-powershell-and-graph-api/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Intune and the rest of Microsoft Intune are growing. To keep your environment nice, clean and secure it is a good idea to monitor your MEM environment.&#xA;In this blog, I explain how to monitor Intune based on Graph API and PowerShell with Azure Functions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using LaMetric Time to monitor an AVD environment</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/using-lametric-time-to-monitor-an-avd-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 16:38:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/using-lametric-time-to-monitor-an-avd-environment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of people in the Microsoft community are using a fancy gadget called LaMetric Time. It is a smart clock which can show time, receiving notifications from a lot of different environments and more. In this blog I will show how to use LaMetric Time to monitor a AVD environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disaster recovery plan for Azure Key Vault using tags, PowerShell and Azure Function</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/disaster-recovery-plan-for-azure-key-vault-using-tags-powershell-and-azure-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 05:37:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/disaster-recovery-plan-for-azure-key-vault-using-tags-powershell-and-azure-function/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By default the Azure Key Vault has softdelete enabled with a 90 day retention. This option will protect Key Vault items when deleted by accident. When deleted you are able to restore that item through the portal or PowerShell.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;But what if someone has deleted the Key Vault itself with all the items and softdeleted items included. There is no option to restore a Key Vault. In this article I will describe a way how to backup and restore a Key Vault when deleted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitor active M365 ServiceHealth services only with PowerShell</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/monitor-active-m365-servicehealth-services-only-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 11:55:44 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/monitor-active-m365-servicehealth-services-only-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You have some Microsoft 365 (M365) customers which you like to monitor. Every day you are looking at the customer specific M365 portal looking for Microsoft event.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;Logging in &lt;/mark&gt;at the&lt;mark&gt; customers portal isn’t a very efficient way.&lt;/mark&gt; &lt;mark&gt;Microsoft provides a lot of API’s which can be used for monitoring.&lt;/mark&gt; By combining some of them you are able to do some really nice and smart things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
