<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microsoft M365 on Sander Rozemuller | All about Automation, Monitoring for Identity, AVD and Intune</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/microsoft-m365/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microsoft M365 on Sander Rozemuller | All about Automation, Monitoring for Identity, AVD and Intune</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 20:08:27 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/microsoft-m365/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Azure Virtual Desktop Image Management Automated – Part 4 AVD Clean up unused resources</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/avd-clean-up-unused-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 20:08:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/avd-clean-up-unused-resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The current situation, we have created new disks, snapshots, virtual machines, networks, images and session hosts. All the resources has been added to the existing AVD hostpool. Now it is time to cleanup the old resources, to keep everything nice and clean. In this part we will take care of removing components related to the old image version.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitor active M365 ServiceHealth services only with PowerShell</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/monitor-active-m365-servicehealth-services-only-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 11:55:44 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/monitor-active-m365-servicehealth-services-only-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You have some Microsoft 365 (M365) customers which you like to monitor. Every day you are looking at the customer specific M365 portal looking for Microsoft event.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;Logging in &lt;/mark&gt;at the&lt;mark&gt; customers portal isn’t a very efficient way.&lt;/mark&gt; &lt;mark&gt;Microsoft provides a lot of API’s which can be used for monitoring.&lt;/mark&gt; By combining some of them you are able to do some really nice and smart things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to use REST API with Powershell</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/how-to-use-rest-api-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 11:57:34 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/how-to-use-rest-api-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The past few years REST API became important more and more. REST API is a common way for communicating against and between applications. Azure and Microsoft 365 also using REST API’s.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;As the world of API is growing so the tooling for querying API’s is growing with the most well known tool is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.postman.com/&#34;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&#xA; &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&gt;Postman&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
