<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security on Sander Rozemuller | All about Automation, Monitoring for Identity, AVD and Intune</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security on Sander Rozemuller | All about Automation, Monitoring for Identity, AVD and Intune</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 09:28:14 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Add Windows Cloud Login application to Conditional Access automated</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/add-windows-cloud-login-application-to-ca-automated/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 09:28:14 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/add-windows-cloud-login-application-to-ca-automated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Single Sign On (SSO) for Azure Virtual Desktop (AVD) gives users a seamless login experience from their Windows 10 or Windows 11 device to AVD. This feature is available for a while and most people have configured this feature already. Also, most are also using Conditional Access (CA) (I hope). To make Single Sign On work for AVD in combination with CA policies you need to add the applications &lt;code&gt;Microsoft Remote Desktop (a4a365df-50f1-4397-bc59-1a1564b8bb9c)&lt;/code&gt; to your CA policies. Based on your situation the applications are in- or excluded.&#xA;Now, Microsoft announced that the Single Sign On traffic will be transitioned from the &lt;code&gt;Microsoft Remote Desktop&lt;/code&gt; app to &lt;code&gt;Windows Cloud Login&lt;/code&gt;. This means you have to add this application to your CA policies. This can be done manually, but I prefer to automate this. In this blog post, I will show you how to add the &lt;code&gt;Windows Cloud Login&lt;/code&gt; application to your CA policies automated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitor Security Baseline Insights Recommendations</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/monitor-security-baseline-insights-recommendations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 16:28:14 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/monitor-security-baseline-insights-recommendations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has updated their security baselines in Microsoft Intune which you can read in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/mem/intune/fundamentals/whats-new#updated-security-baseline-for-windows-version-23h2&#34;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&#xA; &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&gt;What is new in Intune&lt;/a&gt;. A part of the updates is that Microsoft has added recommended settings based on your organisation. In this blog post, I show how to monitor these recommendations that are part of the security baseline and generate a response when a setting does not met Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Route AVD traffic through static WAN IP with Azure Firewall automated</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/route-avd-traffic-static-wan-ip-with-azure-firewall-automated/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 07:55:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/route-avd-traffic-static-wan-ip-with-azure-firewall-automated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I had a situation where a customer asked me how to make sure the AVD environment always has the same WAN IP. To give Azure Virtual Desktop a fixed external IP, some options are available. Think about a NAT gateway or an Azure Firewall. In this blog post, I show how to configure a static WAN IP for AVD with the use of the Azure Firewall in an automated way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use internal main.iam.ad API with Logic Apps</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/use-internal-azure-api-with-logic-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 11:46:12 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/use-internal-azure-api-with-logic-apps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog post is a follow-up to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rozemuller.com/use-internal-azure-api-in-automation/&#34;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&#xA; &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&gt;my post about using the hidden API in automation&lt;/a&gt;. In that post, I explained how to authenticate to the &lt;code&gt;https://main.iam.ad.ext.azure.com/api/&lt;/code&gt; endpoint and, how to get information from it. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already, I would suggest reading that post first.&#xA;I used Azure Functions to run the automation tasks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use internal main.iam.ad API in automation</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/use-internal-azure-api-in-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 11:46:12 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/use-internal-azure-api-in-automation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We all know the Graph API, graph.microsoft.com, and the Azure management API, management.azure.com. Both APIs are used very often and lots of automation tasks depend on those APIs. Also, most PowerShell modules rely on them and, the Graph and Azure management APIs are well documented.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secure and optimize AVD and CloudPC using Microsoft Intune</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/secure-and-optimize-avd-and-cloudpc-using-microsoft-endpoint-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 12:39:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/secure-and-optimize-avd-and-cloudpc-using-microsoft-endpoint-manager/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, I explain how to secure and optimize AVD and CloudPC environment using Microsoft Intune automated. The configuration is all deployed automated based on PowerShell, JSON templates, and Graph API. I explain how to create a security baseline and how to deploy a configuration profile with settings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configure Azure Firewall Premium features for AVD automated</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/configure-azure-firewall-premium-features-for-avd-automated/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 17:02:43 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/configure-azure-firewall-premium-features-for-avd-automated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Security became important more and more. It is recommend, now the days arrived where the most people work from home and IT is moving to the public cloud, to use a good firewall with less complexity as possible. In case of AVD within the current situation an IT environment can be complex. In this article I will explain how configure an Azure Firewall for AVD automated with premium options, which came in public preview at 16 February 2021. At the end I will show how to deploy an Azure Firewall specially for a AVD environment with all the needed steps automated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enable Screen Capture Protection for Azure Virtual Desktop Automated</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/enable-screen-capture-protection-for-azure-virtual-desktop-automated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 13:02:03 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/enable-screen-capture-protection-for-azure-virtual-desktop-automated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Working remotely has a lot of advantages like less travel time, more focus to work (when the house is not full of kids :)), which contributes to working efficiently. But there are some concerns about security, and rightly so I think. Especially when you are used to ‘see’ what happens on the screen in real life which help at least you think you are in control of your data. In this article I will show how to enable AVD screen protection automated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
