<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ARM Templates on Sander Rozemuller | All about Identity, AVD, Automation, DevOps, Monitoring, Intune and Security</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/tags/arm-templates/</link><description>Recent content in ARM Templates on Sander Rozemuller | All about Identity, AVD, Automation, DevOps, Monitoring, Intune and Security</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 15:10:27 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.rozemuller.com/tags/arm-templates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AVD Automation Cocktail - Azure Virtual Desktop automated with DevOps and ARM</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-devops-and-arm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 15:13:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-devops-and-arm/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the AVD Automation Cocktail. In this cocktail series I will show different AVD deployment strategies and languages. In this cocktail, the Strawberry Banana Mix, I will show you how to deploy an AVD environment automated with DevOps, ARM templates and a bit of PowerShell.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Automatically backup Azure resources to an Azure Storage Account in JSON</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/automatically-backup-azure-resources-to-an-azure-storage-account-in-json/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 08:04:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/automatically-backup-azure-resources-to-an-azure-storage-account-in-json/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this quick blog post I will explain a way how to backup Azure resources and how to restore them with PowerShell, in JSON format, to an Azure Storage Account which is “deployment ready”.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Enable Screen Capture Protection for Azure Virtual Desktop Automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/enable-screen-capture-protection-for-azure-virtual-desktop-automated/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 13:02:03 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/enable-screen-capture-protection-for-azure-virtual-desktop-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>Working remotely has a lot of advantages like less travel time, more focus to work (when the house is not full of kids :)), which contributes to working efficiently. But there are some concerns about security, and rightly so I think. Especially when you are used to ‘see’ what happens on the screen in real life which help at least you think you are in control of your data. In this article I will show how to enable AVD screen protection automated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Disaster recovery plan for Azure Key Vault using tags, PowerShell and Azure Function</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/disaster-recovery-plan-for-azure-key-vault-using-tags-powershell-and-azure-function/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 05:37:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/disaster-recovery-plan-for-azure-key-vault-using-tags-powershell-and-azure-function/</guid><description>&lt;p>By default the Azure Key Vault has softdelete enabled with a 90 day retention. This option will protect Key Vault items when deleted by accident. When deleted you are able to restore that item through the portal or PowerShell.&lt;br>
But what if someone has deleted the Key Vault itself with all the items and softdeleted items included. There is no option to restore a Key Vault. In this article I will describe a way how to backup and restore a Key Vault when deleted.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to use Key Vault ARM templates and deal with sensitive parameters</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/how-to-use-keyvault-arm-templates-and-deal-with-sensitive-parameters/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 18:19:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/how-to-use-keyvault-arm-templates-and-deal-with-sensitive-parameters/</guid><description>&lt;p>At October 14, 2020 Mircosoft &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/key-vault/keys/quick-create-template?tabs=CLI"




 target="_blank"
 


>announced&lt;/a>
 the public preview of ARM templates for adding secrets to Azure Key Vault. In this article I will explain a way how to use these templates.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Azure Virtual Desktop Image Management Automated - Part 3 Create AVD sessionhosts on image version with ARM</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/create-avd-sessionhosts-based-on-shared-image-gallery-version-with-arm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 12:05:45 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/create-avd-sessionhosts-based-on-shared-image-gallery-version-with-arm/</guid><description>&lt;p>This article is serie of posts about AVD Image Management Automated. In this part we are going to add new sessionhosts to an existing AVD hostpool based on a ARM template.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>