<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microsoft Intune on Sander Rozemuller | All about Automation, Monitoring for Identity, AVD and Intune</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/categories/microsoft-intune/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microsoft Intune on Sander Rozemuller | All about Automation, Monitoring for Identity, AVD and Intune</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 09:28:14 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/microsoft-intune/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automated Device Group Management for Microsoft Intune Update Rings Using PowerShell</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/automated-device-group-management-for-microsoft-intune-update-rings-using-powerShell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 09:28:14 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/automated-device-group-management-for-microsoft-intune-update-rings-using-powerShell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Testing settings and updates in Microsoft Intune is a good idea. Many Intune administrators use a test group and Deployment Rings for this. In the case of Windows Updates, administrators configure an update ring and assign a group to it. The group is filled with devices (I call it a device group).&#xA;In this blog post, I will show you how to dynamically manage a device group in an automated way for your Intune update rings based on&#xA;a user group. Let&amp;rsquo;s call it dynamic device group management.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitor Security Baseline Insights Recommendations</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/monitor-security-baseline-insights-recommendations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 16:28:14 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/monitor-security-baseline-insights-recommendations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has updated their security baselines in Microsoft Intune which you can read in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/mem/intune/fundamentals/whats-new#updated-security-baseline-for-windows-version-23h2&#34;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&#xA; &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&gt;What is new in Intune&lt;/a&gt;. A part of the updates is that Microsoft has added recommended settings based on your organisation. In this blog post, I show how to monitor these recommendations that are part of the security baseline and generate a response when a setting does not met Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The IntuneCLI for automated Intune management</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-intunecli-for-automated-intune-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 02:44:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-intunecli-for-automated-intune-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Managing Intune can be challenging, especially when having multiple Microsoft Intune environments. Because of that, I started project IntuneAssistant. A part of the project is a CLI tool that can run as a daemon in your own environment.&#xA;In this small blog, I explain how to use the CLI and what are my thoughts for the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Update Intune filters with Windows 11 23H2 build automated</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/update-intune-filters-with-windows11-23h2-build-automated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 07:44:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/update-intune-filters-with-windows11-23h2-build-automated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you also may know is that using filters in Intune is a best practise. With the come of the Windows 11 23H2 build number it is a good idea 💡 to update your filters by adding the new 10.22631.x build number. In this blog post, I show how to update all Windows 11 filters with the new build number using PowerShell and the Graph API.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Windows Store (winget) App Not Supported in Preview in Intune</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/windows-store-app-not-supported-in-preview-in-Intune/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 07:32:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/windows-store-app-not-supported-in-preview-in-Intune/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The new Windows Store App feature (aka WinGet installation) becomes more popular. However, this feature is still in preview. That means that not all is working as expected. Adding these applications using the portal has dependencies. One of those things is that an applications needs a valid version. Something not every application has.&#xA;The results in an error like:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configure AVD using settings catalog automated</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/configure-avd-using-settings-catalog-automated/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 20:14:59 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/configure-avd-using-settings-catalog-automated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this blog about configuring Azure Virtual Desktop session host with Microsoft Intune. The Intune settings catalog is growing very fast and now also AVD settings making it to the settings catalog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Import Reuseable EPM Certificates in Intune automated </title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/import-reusable-epm-certificates-in-intune-automated/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 16:39:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/import-reusable-epm-certificates-in-intune-automated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you may know there is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.com/invite/msems&#34;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&#xA; &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&gt;Microsoft EMS Community&lt;/a&gt; Discord channel where we help out eachother. Recently there was a question about how to import certificate file as reusable setting in Endpoint Privilege Management using the Graph API. Together with Steven van Beek we answered that question on how to bulk import certificates using the Graph API. To also help others I like to share the solution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Passwordless, Multi-layered Break Glass Alternative Automated</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/passwordless-multilayered-break-glass-alternative-automated/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 09:15:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/passwordless-multilayered-break-glass-alternative-automated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Emergency accounts are a fundamental part of any security strategy. They are used to access systems when the primary account is unavailable or locked out. In the past, emergency accounts were often called “break glass” accounts. In an earlier post, I explained &lt;a href=&#34;../configure-break-glass-accounts-infrastructure-automated/&#34;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA; &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&gt;how to create an emergency account based on a user account with a password&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, I will show you how to automate the creation of a passwordless, multi-layered emergency account using Graph API.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zero Trust Data Protection Using App Protection Policies Automated</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/zero-trust-data-protection-using-app-protection-policies-automated/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 20:40:49 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/zero-trust-data-protection-using-app-protection-policies-automated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In earlier steps, I explained how to control identity and devices to connect to your environment. Now people are connected to your environment safely, the next step is to make sure your data won&amp;rsquo;t walk out.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;In this step of the Zero to Zero Trust journey we will look at the first step of how to keep your data safe. In this blog, I show how to automate the creation of App Protection Policies. Intune App Protection policies help protect corporate data even if a device itself is not managed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get Intune Device Management Scripts Content using Graph</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/get-intune-device-management-scripts-content-using-graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 14:55:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/get-intune-device-management-scripts-content-using-graph/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Device management scripts in Intune are custom scripts that can run on Windows 10 and higher clients and  MacOS. The ability to run scripts on local devices gives you an alternative to configuring devices with settings that are not available under the configuration policies or in the apps part of Intune.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Win32LOB intunewin file upload process explained for automation</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/win32lob-intunewin-file-upload-process-explained-for-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 01:28:14 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/win32lob-intunewin-file-upload-process-explained-for-automation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details class=&#34;table-of-content&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;summary&gt;Table Of Contents&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;  &lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;ul&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#create-win32lob-app-portal-process&#34;&gt;Create Win32LOB App portal process&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;      &lt;ul&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#create-win32lob-app-in-intune&#34;&gt;Create Win32LOB App in Intune&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#request-intunewin-file-version&#34;&gt;Request intunewin file version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#upload-and-commit-intunewin-file-to-azure-storage-blob&#34;&gt;Upload and commit intunewin file to Azure Storage Blob&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#create-win32lob-app-in-automation&#34;&gt;Create Win32LOB App in automation&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;      &lt;ul&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#create-win32lob-app-in-intune-automated&#34;&gt;Create Win32LOB App in Intune automated&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#request-intunewin-file-version-1&#34;&gt;Request intunewin file version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#create-place-holder-for-intunewin-file-version-automated&#34;&gt;Create place holder for intunewin file version automated&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#upload-file-to-win32-lob-app-automated&#34;&gt;Upload file to Win32 LOB App automated&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/nav&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few days ago a question reached me about creating Win32Lob applications including the &lt;code&gt;intunewin&lt;/code&gt; file upload using the REST API. The &lt;code&gt;create&lt;/code&gt; Win32Lob Graph API has no object available to store a file in, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/graph/api/intune-apps-win32lobapp-create?view=graph-rest-beta&#34;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&#xA; &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&gt;the documentation&lt;/a&gt; doesn&amp;rsquo;t explain how to upload files while creating Win32Lob applications automated.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;That decided me to look into the file upload process and write this blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Add Microsoft Store (WinGet) app with icon into Intune automated</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/add-microsoft-store-app-with-icon-into-intune-automated/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 01:28:14 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/add-microsoft-store-app-with-icon-into-intune-automated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the week of November 28, 2022, Microsoft released the new Microsoft Store which is implemented in Intune using the Windows Packager Manager. This is because the Microsoft Store for Business will be deprecated in the first quarter of 2023.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It is a great feature that helps distribute applications in a very simple way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Route own Intune data to Log Analytics using custom logs</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/route-own-intune-data-to-log-analytics-using-custom-logs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 09:28:48 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/route-own-intune-data-to-log-analytics-using-custom-logs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I often write blogs about getting data with the Graph API and using it for monitoring. A while ago I was thinking about how to get my own data into Log Analytics.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;In this blog post, I show how to ingest custom MEM data into a Log Analytics table. I also show how to configure all components in an automated way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitor Intune using Azure Functions, PowerShell, Graph API and MS Teams</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/monitor-intune-using-azure-functions-powershell-and-graph-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 09:12:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/monitor-intune-using-azure-functions-powershell-and-graph-api/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Intune and the rest of Microsoft Intune are growing. To keep your environment nice, clean and secure it is a good idea to monitor your MEM environment.&#xA;In this blog, I explain how to monitor Intune based on Graph API and PowerShell with Azure Functions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Intune settings catalog automated from scratch with Graph API</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/deploy-intune-settings-catalog-automated-from-scratch-with-graph-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 07:55:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/deploy-intune-settings-catalog-automated-from-scratch-with-graph-api/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I show in this blog how to create a device configuration profile based on the settings catalog in Intune. A while ago I&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rozemuller.com/deploy-power-settings-automated-in-microsoft-endpoint-manager/&#34;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&#xA; &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&gt; created a profile with power settings and deployed the profile to all devices including a filter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enable Endpoint Analytics automated in Microsoft Intune</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/enable-endpoint-analytics-automated-in-microsoft-endpoint-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 10:23:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/enable-endpoint-analytics-automated-in-microsoft-endpoint-manager/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy users are key. But with all the changes in hardware, software distributions, security- and OS updates, it could take a lot of effort. Now remote working is embedded into our culture it costs even more effort to keep sight of what is happening. Endpoint analytics gives you insight into how the organization is working and the quality of experience which is delivered to users. I show how to enable endpoint analytics automated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intune filters explained create automated and assignments</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/intune-filters-explained-and-create-automated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 15:36:16 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/intune-filters-explained-and-create-automated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Intune filters are a great way to assign MEM policies to devices. In fact, filters go over groups in several scenarios. Filters help you keep your environment reliable and fast. In this blog, I do some basic explanations about filters, how to use filters, and show how to create Intune filters in an automated way. At last, I show how to assign filters to policies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitor and get alerts from Microsoft Intune</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/monitor-and-get-alerts-from-microsoft-endpoint-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 11:14:54 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/monitor-and-get-alerts-from-microsoft-endpoint-manager/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Out of the box, Microsoft Intune has a reporting platform where lots of information is stored. Think about device management or endpoint analytics. For troubleshooting, reports can help. However, if you need to troubleshoot you are too late in the first place. It would be nice to get alerts out of Microsoft Intune. Luckily, there are options to achieve that goal. In this post, I show a way to monitor and get alerts from Microsoft Intune.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitor security baselines in Endpoint Security</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/monitor-security-baselines-in-endpoint-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 08:58:35 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/monitor-security-baselines-in-endpoint-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A security baseline has some values which are interesting to know. It has a status that tells us the current deployment status if a profile is assigned or is deprecated. In this post, I show how to monitor security baselines. The current status, versions, and if a profile is assigned. I will explain which data is important, how to get the data and show different ways to send alerts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configure subscribe to AVD in RDP Client automated</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/configure-subscribe-to-avd-in-rdp-client-automated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 11:45:40 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/configure-subscribe-to-avd-in-rdp-client-automated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Azure Virtual Desktop (AVD) is a great addition to your IT environment. To connect to an AVD environment you need a browser or the Remote Desktop client. When using the browser you have to go to the ‘rdweb’-URL. When using the remote desktop client, you need to subscribe to a workplace. In this blog post, I show how to configure the subscribe URL for AVD automated. How to configure this setting in MEM automated. Also, I show a way to deploy the setting if you are not using MEM.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploy power settings automated in Microsoft Intune</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/deploy-power-settings-automated-in-microsoft-endpoint-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 16:23:52 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/deploy-power-settings-automated-in-microsoft-endpoint-manager/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Climate changes are the talk of the day. Every little step to help the world is great. Power consumption is a big topic in those discussions. In this blog post, I show how to deploy power management settings automated in Microsoft Intune. This is to save battery on hardware devices. I also show how to assign the policy to the devices part with a filter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Intune security baselines explained</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/microsoft-endpoint-manager-security-baselines-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 16:09:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/microsoft-endpoint-manager-security-baselines-explained/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During writing automation blog posts about deploying security baselines automated, I felt the need to write a new blog about how these security baselines actually work. Not in the way how security baselines are deployed but how security baselines are built. Which components does a baseline have and how do settings fit together. In this blog post, I peel off a security baseline and explain how to grab the correct settings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secure and optimize AVD and CloudPC using Microsoft Intune</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/secure-and-optimize-avd-and-cloudpc-using-microsoft-endpoint-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 12:39:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/secure-and-optimize-avd-and-cloudpc-using-microsoft-endpoint-manager/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, I explain how to secure and optimize AVD and CloudPC environment using Microsoft Intune automated. The configuration is all deployed automated based on PowerShell, JSON templates, and Graph API. I explain how to create a security baseline and how to deploy a configuration profile with settings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distribute OneDrive with Winget and OneDrive best practices automated</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/distribute-onedrive-with-winget-and-onedrive-best-practices-automated/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 14:13:27 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/distribute-onedrive-with-winget-and-onedrive-best-practices-automated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this article, I explain how to distribute OneDrive with Microsoft Endpoint Managed based on Winget. After deploying OneDrive I configure a settings catalog configuration policy. This policy has all the OneDrive best practices. At last, a sync device is triggered.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install Winget applications using Microsoft Intune</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/install-winget-applications-using-microsoft-endpoint-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 09:14:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/install-winget-applications-using-microsoft-endpoint-manager/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post, I will show how to install applications with Windows Package Manager (or Winget), within Microsft Endpoint Manager. This is all done by one single executable package which accepts the application name and version. Or providing a manifest location. Using one single file avoids creating single packages and intunewin-files every time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manage Windows Updates for AVD using Microsoft Intune</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/manage-windows-updates-for-avd-using-microsoft-endpoint-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 22:44:52 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/manage-windows-updates-for-avd-using-microsoft-endpoint-manager/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this article, I explain a way how to manage Windows Updates for Azure Virtual Desktop (AVD). To achieve this goal I use update rings in Microsoft Intune. These update rings will be assigned to a dynamic Azure AD group. I also show how to create and assign this configuration automated with the use of PowerShell.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manage AVD automated with Microsoft Intune</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/manage-avd-automated-with-microsoft-endpoint-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 14:11:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/manage-avd-automated-with-microsoft-endpoint-manager/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to a brand new series called Operation North Star. In the upcoming series, I will show how to manage AVD environments with Microsoft Intune. I talk about how to manage AVD environments and how to deploy these settings automated. At last, I try to show how to configure a new way of management.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
