<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Zero Trust on Sander Rozemuller | All about Identity, AVD, Automation, DevOps, Monitoring, Intune and Security</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/categories/zero-trust/</link><description>Recent content in Zero Trust on Sander Rozemuller | All about Identity, AVD, Automation, DevOps, Monitoring, Intune and Security</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 17:08:11 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.rozemuller.com/categories/zero-trust/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configure AVD clipboard transfer direction automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/configure-avd-clipboard-transfer-direction-automated/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 01:28:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/configure-avd-clipboard-transfer-direction-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>Using the clipboard between Azure Virtual Desktop and the users client is a great way to send data back and forth. But it is also could big leak into the system. So maybe you want to limit the use of the clipboard or get more control on how the clipboard could be used between the user and the Azure Virtual Desktop enviroment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Check Conditional Access Policy Effect Automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/check-conditional-access-policy-effect-automated/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 20:40:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/check-conditional-access-policy-effect-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>In earlier posts I created several conditional access policies in an automated way. During the time policies may change, users will be added to a specific Azure role, groups are added and so many more.&lt;br>
All those changes effect on how conditional access policies act. Because of that, it is recommended to check your conditional access policies environment so now and then.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Passwordless, Multi-layered Break Glass Alternative Automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/passwordless-multilayered-break-glass-alternative-automated/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 09:15:27 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/passwordless-multilayered-break-glass-alternative-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>Emergency accounts are a fundamental part of any security strategy. They are used to access systems when the primary account is unavailable or locked out. In the past, emergency accounts were often called “break glass” accounts. In an earlier post, I explained &lt;a href="../configure-break-glass-accounts-infrastructure-automated/"



 


>how to create an emergency account based on a user account with a password&lt;/a>
. In this post, I will show you how to automate the creation of a passwordless, multi-layered emergency account using Graph API.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Zero Trust Data Protection Using App Protection Policies Automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/zero-trust-data-protection-using-app-protection-policies-automated/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 20:40:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/zero-trust-data-protection-using-app-protection-policies-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>In earlier steps, I explained how to control identity and devices to connect to your environment. Now people are connected to your environment safely, the next step is to make sure your data won&amp;rsquo;t walk out.&lt;br>
In this step of the Zero to Zero Trust journey we will look at the first step of how to keep your data safe. In this blog, I show how to automate the creation of App Protection Policies. Intune App Protection policies help protect corporate data even if a device itself is not managed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Zero Trust Common Identity and Device Access Protection</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/zero-trust-common-identity-and-device-access-protection/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 13:53:14 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/zero-trust-common-identity-and-device-access-protection/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is the 3rd step in the series Zero to Zero Trust in an automated way. In the previous steps, we configured an emergency account and protected the account with conditional access policies. The conditional access policies control the log-in process. In this step, we configure access policies for other users and devices.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Protect Privileged Accounts the Zero Trust Way Automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/protect-privileged-accounts-the-zero-trust-way-automated/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 09:17:14 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/protect-privileged-accounts-the-zero-trust-way-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>Identities are the key to environments and must be configured as securely as possible. To achieve this goal, conditional access policies are indispensable. In this blog post, I show how to secure privileged accounts that need more attention than MFA only. This post shows how to configure Zero Trust conditional access policies in an automated way.&lt;br>
This is the next step in our Zero to Zero Trust journey.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Configure Break Glass Accounts Infrastructure Automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/configure-break-glass-accounts-infrastructure-automated/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 08:30:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/configure-break-glass-accounts-infrastructure-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>Nowadays a good cloud environment has strict security policies. Well-known policies are conditional access policies. Policies that require a compliant device before login for example or forcing MFA. Configuring conditional access is good but there is always a risk of lockout yourself. To not lock yourself out, you must create an emergency account.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Zero to Zero Trust Automation Index</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/zero-to-zero-trust-automation-index/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 12:43:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/zero-to-zero-trust-automation-index/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the Zero to Zero Trust series automated and to this automation index. In this series, I will show the process from a zero security configuration to Zero Trust in the Microsoft public cloud. The series passes all the important items and show how to configure the components automated if applicable.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>