<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bicep on Sander Rozemuller | All about Automation, Monitoring for Identity, AVD and Intune</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/bicep/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bicep on Sander Rozemuller | All about Automation, Monitoring for Identity, AVD and Intune</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 13:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/bicep/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AVD Automation Cocktail - Azure Virtual Desktop automated with Bicep and Azure CLI</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-with-bicep-and-azure-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-with-bicep-and-azure-cli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the updated AVD Automation Cocktail. This cocktail is updated with all new Bicep and AVD features since september 2023.&#xA;In this cocktail series I will show different AVD deployment strategies and languages. In this cocktail, the Fresh Minty Breeze, I will show you how to deploy an AVD environment automated with Bicep and Azure CLI.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AVD Automation Cocktail - The Menu</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/avd-automation-cocktail-the-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 20:21:49 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/avd-automation-cocktail-the-menu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to a fresh new series about deploying Azure Virtual Desktop environments automated called the “AVD Automation Cocktail”. In this series I will serve several cocktails and will take you along on the AVD automated deployment journey with different types of automation languages. Every type has its own pros and cons, deployment strategy, parameter structure and commands. In the series all of these items will pass and hopefully it will give you a good overview about the possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
