<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cocktail on Sander Rozemuller | All about Automation, Monitoring for Identity, AVD and Intune</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/cocktail/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cocktail on Sander Rozemuller | All about Automation, Monitoring for Identity, AVD and Intune</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 10:16:18 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/cocktail/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AVD Automation Cocktail – Deploy AVD AzureAD with DevOps and Az.Avd</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/avd-automation-cocktail-deploy-avd-azuread-with-devops-and-az-avd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 10:16:18 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/avd-automation-cocktail-deploy-avd-azuread-with-devops-and-az-avd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the AVD Automation Cocktail. In this cocktail series, I will show different AVD deployment strategies and languages. In this cocktail, Santa’s Tree Ride, I will show you how to deploy an AzureAD joined only AVD environment automated with DevOps and the Az.Avd PowerShell module.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AVD Automation Cocktail – Deploy AVD with Terraform Cloud</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-terraform-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 10:41:34 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-terraform-cloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome (back) to the AVD Automation Cocktail. In the past &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-the-menu&#34;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&#xA; &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&gt;cocktail series&lt;/a&gt;, I showed different AVD deployment strategies and languages. During the time I got some requests about automation with Terraform. In this cocktail, The Dutch Bloody Harry, I’ll show you how to deploy an AVD environment automated with Terraform Cloud and Github. I’m using the Terraform cloud combined with my GitHub repository.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AVD Automation Cocktail – AVD automated with Azure CLI</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-azure-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 14:59:39 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-azure-cli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the AVD Automation Cocktail. In this cocktail series I will show different AVD deployment strategies and languages. In this cocktail, the Sweet Orange Sunset, I will show you how to deploy an AVD environment automated with Azure CLI. Great new feature in this cocktail is the Azure AAD Join feature.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AVD Automation Cocktail - Azure Virtual Desktop automated with REST API</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-rest-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 16:10:50 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-rest-api/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the AVD Automation Cocktail. In this cocktail series, I will show different AVD deployment strategies and languages. In this cocktail, the Pineapple Citrus Splash, I will show you how to deploy an AVD environment automated with REST API, and JSON executed with PowerShell.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AVD Automation Cocktail - Azure Virtual Desktop automated with DevOps and ARM</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-devops-and-arm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 15:13:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-devops-and-arm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the AVD Automation Cocktail. In this cocktail series I will show different AVD deployment strategies and languages. In this cocktail, the Strawberry Banana Mix, I will show you how to deploy an AVD environment automated with DevOps, ARM templates and a bit of PowerShell.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AVD Automation Cocktail - Azure Virtual Desktop automated with PowerShell</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 11:28:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the AVD Automation Cocktail. In this cocktail series, I will show different AVD deployment strategies and languages. In this cocktail, the Coconut Beach Party, I will show you how to deploy an AVD environment automated with PowerShell only.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AVD Automation Cocktail - Azure Virtual Desktop automated with Bicep and Azure CLI</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-with-bicep-and-azure-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-with-bicep-and-azure-cli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the updated AVD Automation Cocktail. This cocktail is updated with all new Bicep and AVD features since september 2023.&#xA;In this cocktail series I will show different AVD deployment strategies and languages. In this cocktail, the Fresh Minty Breeze, I will show you how to deploy an AVD environment automated with Bicep and Azure CLI.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AVD Automation Cocktail - The Menu</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/avd-automation-cocktail-the-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 20:21:49 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/avd-automation-cocktail-the-menu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to a fresh new series about deploying Azure Virtual Desktop environments automated called the “AVD Automation Cocktail”. In this series I will serve several cocktails and will take you along on the AVD automated deployment journey with different types of automation languages. Every type has its own pros and cons, deployment strategy, parameter structure and commands. In the series all of these items will pass and hopefully it will give you a good overview about the possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
