<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DevOps on Sander Rozemuller | All about Automation, Monitoring for Identity, AVD and Intune</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/categories/devops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DevOps on Sander Rozemuller | All about Automation, Monitoring for Identity, AVD and Intune</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 20:41:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The DevOps Project Clone a pipeline from a source project automated</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-devops-project-clone-a-pipeline-from-a-source-project-automated/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 20:41:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-devops-project-clone-a-pipeline-from-a-source-project-automated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this 4th slice of Prepare Azure DevOps for AVD deployment series, I will show how to copy or clone an existing YAML pipeline automated from a source project into a new AVD project. This will help you keep one main pipeline as a source and will allow you to create a “linked” pipeline into a new project directly from the source.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AVD Automation Cocktail - Azure Virtual Desktop automated with DevOps and ARM</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-devops-and-arm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 15:13:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-devops-and-arm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the AVD Automation Cocktail. In this cocktail series I will show different AVD deployment strategies and languages. In this cocktail, the Strawberry Banana Mix, I will show you how to deploy an AVD environment automated with DevOps, ARM templates and a bit of PowerShell.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to configure dynamic recipients in DevOps environments</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/how-to-configure-dynamic-recipients-in-devops-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 15:33:57 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/how-to-configure-dynamic-recipients-in-devops-environments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in earlier posts Azure DevOps is a really nice way to deploy Azure resources automated. During my travel through Azure DevOps for managing Windows Virtual Desktop resources I moved from classic pipelines and releases to the new YAML pipelines. Using YAML has a lot of advantages in relation to classic. But there are some new challenges coming, approval or manual interventions for example. In this article I will explain how to use approvals and checks with dynamic recipients in DevOps environments within a YAML configuration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prepare Azure DevOps for AVD deployment – Create a Service Connection Automated</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/prepare-azure-devops-for-avd-deployment-create-a-service-connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 11:28:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/prepare-azure-devops-for-avd-deployment-create-a-service-connection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using Azure DevOps is a really nice way to deploy resources in Azure, so also for Windows Virtual Desktop. Before you are able to deploy resources into Azure with pipelines you will need to setup a project and a service connection first. In post I will explain how to create a DevOps Service Connection the automated way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prepare Azure DevOps for Azure Virtual Desktop deployment – Create DevOps project</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/prepare-azure-devops-for-azure-virtual-desktop-deployment-create-devops-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 16:02:21 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/prepare-azure-devops-for-azure-virtual-desktop-deployment-create-devops-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An Azure DevOps environment consists of projects. Before create anything in DevOps like a board, repositories or pipelines you first need a project. In this second part of the series Prepare Azure DevOps for Azure Virtual Desktop we are diving into that DevOps part, a project. At the end of this post you will be able to deploy WVD with DevOps automated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
