<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Entra ID on Sander Rozemuller | All about Identity, AVD, Automation, DevOps, Monitoring, Intune and Security</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/tags/entra-id/</link><description>Recent content in Entra ID on Sander Rozemuller | All about Identity, AVD, Automation, DevOps, Monitoring, Intune and Security</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 15:09:51 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.rozemuller.com/tags/entra-id/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Check Conditional Access Policy Effect Automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/check-conditional-access-policy-effect-automated/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 20:40:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/check-conditional-access-policy-effect-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>In earlier posts I created several conditional access policies in an automated way. During the time policies may change, users will be added to a specific Azure role, groups are added and so many more.&lt;br>
All those changes effect on how conditional access policies act. Because of that, it is recommended to check your conditional access policies environment so now and then.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Zero Trust Data Protection Using App Protection Policies Automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/zero-trust-data-protection-using-app-protection-policies-automated/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 20:40:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/zero-trust-data-protection-using-app-protection-policies-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>In earlier steps, I explained how to control identity and devices to connect to your environment. Now people are connected to your environment safely, the next step is to make sure your data won&amp;rsquo;t walk out.&lt;br>
In this step of the Zero to Zero Trust journey we will look at the first step of how to keep your data safe. In this blog, I show how to automate the creation of App Protection Policies. Intune App Protection policies help protect corporate data even if a device itself is not managed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Zero Trust Common Identity and Device Access Protection</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/zero-trust-common-identity-and-device-access-protection/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 13:53:14 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/zero-trust-common-identity-and-device-access-protection/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is the 3rd step in the series Zero to Zero Trust in an automated way. In the previous steps, we configured an emergency account and protected the account with conditional access policies. The conditional access policies control the log-in process. In this step, we configure access policies for other users and devices.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Protect Privileged Accounts the Zero Trust Way Automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/protect-privileged-accounts-the-zero-trust-way-automated/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 09:17:14 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/protect-privileged-accounts-the-zero-trust-way-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>Identities are the key to environments and must be configured as securely as possible. To achieve this goal, conditional access policies are indispensable. In this blog post, I show how to secure privileged accounts that need more attention than MFA only. This post shows how to configure Zero Trust conditional access policies in an automated way.&lt;br>
This is the next step in our Zero to Zero Trust journey.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Configure Break Glass Accounts Infrastructure Automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/configure-break-glass-accounts-infrastructure-automated/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 08:30:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/configure-break-glass-accounts-infrastructure-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>Nowadays a good cloud environment has strict security policies. Well-known policies are conditional access policies. Policies that require a compliant device before login for example or forcing MFA. Configuring conditional access is good but there is always a risk of lockout yourself. To not lock yourself out, you must create an emergency account.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Zero to Zero Trust Automation Index</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/zero-to-zero-trust-automation-index/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 12:43:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/zero-to-zero-trust-automation-index/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the Zero to Zero Trust series automated and to this automation index. In this series, I will show the process from a zero security configuration to Zero Trust in the Microsoft public cloud. The series passes all the important items and show how to configure the components automated if applicable.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Endpoint Security Train - Introduction</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/the-endpoint-security-train-introduction/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 07:38:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/the-endpoint-security-train-introduction/</guid><description>&lt;p>The IT landscape is changing. Private becomes public, local resources are moving to the public cloud. More and more workloads return to the local endpoint. Cloud endpoints (AVD, W365) are mostly used to run legacy software.
With all those movements, it could be challenging to keep the herd in the pasture. Devices are everywhere and what about security?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Disable user tenant creation</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/disable-user-tenant-creation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 20:38:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/disable-user-tenant-creation/</guid><description>&lt;p>It looks like Microsoft has added a new option that allows users to create tenants. Some people have seen the Tenant Creation option in the regular Azure portal but was removed fast. For now, the option is still available in the Preview Azure Portal (&lt;a href="https://preview.portal.azure.com/"




 target="_blank"
 


>https://preview.portal.azure.com/&lt;/a>
)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Configure FSLogix profile for Azure AD joined AVD session host automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/configure-fslogix-profile-for-azure-ad-joined-avd-session-host-automated/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 14:34:21 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/configure-fslogix-profile-for-azure-ad-joined-avd-session-host-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this blog post, I explain how to configure FSLogix for Azure AD-joined machines automated. Also, I explain how to test the configuration and I rearranged the installation procedure in a more efficient way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to join Azure AD automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/how-to-join-azure-ad-automated/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 16:55:50 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/how-to-join-azure-ad-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this article, I show how to deploy and join an Azure VM to Azure AD join automated. In the deployment, I use two different ways of deployment. I use PowerShell and Azure CLI. Additionally, I show how to install the AVD extension with the Azure AD join.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AVD Automation Cocktail – AVD automated with Azure CLI</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-azure-cli/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 14:59:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-azure-cli/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the AVD Automation Cocktail. In this cocktail series I will show different AVD deployment strategies and languages. In this cocktail, the Sweet Orange Sunset, I will show you how to deploy an AVD environment automated with Azure CLI. Great new feature in this cocktail is the Azure AAD Join feature.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Configure AVD Start VM on Connect automated with role assignments and Graph API</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/configure-avd-start-vm-on-connect-automated-with-role-assignments-and-graph-api/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 15:46:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/configure-avd-start-vm-on-connect-automated-with-role-assignments-and-graph-api/</guid><description>&lt;p>Costs are a topic of an Azure conversation very often. As we all know you pay for usage, if it is storage, CPU or bandwidth usage, (almost) every resource has its price. For Windows Virtual Desktop it means you have to pay for CPU usage, for example. It is important then to keep this usage as low as possible. Now there is an option to keep these usage as low as possible with AVD Start VM on Connect.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prepare Azure DevOps for Azure Virtual Desktop deployment - App registration</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/prepare-azure-devops-for-windows-virtual-desktop-deployment-app-registration/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 10:40:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/prepare-azure-devops-for-windows-virtual-desktop-deployment-app-registration/</guid><description>&lt;p>Using Azure DevOps is a really nice way to deploy resources in Azure, so also for Azure Virtual Desktop. Before you are able to deploy resources into Azure with pipelines you will need to setup a project and a service connection first. While configuring a service connection you will be asked for some specific tenant details.&lt;br>
In this short series I will explain every step you need to prepare DevOps for AVD deployment.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>