<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Azure Virtual Desktop on Sander Rozemuller | All about Identity, AVD, Automation, DevOps, Monitoring, Intune and Security</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/tags/azure-virtual-desktop/</link><description>Recent content in Azure Virtual Desktop on Sander Rozemuller | All about Identity, AVD, Automation, DevOps, Monitoring, Intune and Security</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 11:30:29 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.rozemuller.com/tags/azure-virtual-desktop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Add Windows Cloud Login application to Conditional Access automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/add-windows-cloud-login-application-to-ca-automated/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 09:28:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/add-windows-cloud-login-application-to-ca-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>Single Sign On (SSO) for Azure Virtual Desktop (AVD) gives users a seamless login experience from their Windows 10 or Windows 11 device to AVD. This feature is available for a while and most people have configured this feature already. Also, most are also using Conditional Access (CA) (I hope). To make Single Sign On work for AVD in combination with CA policies you need to add the applications &lt;code>Microsoft Remote Desktop (a4a365df-50f1-4397-bc59-1a1564b8bb9c)&lt;/code> to your CA policies. Based on your situation the applications are in- or excluded.
Now, Microsoft announced that the Single Sign On traffic will be transitioned from the &lt;code>Microsoft Remote Desktop&lt;/code> app to &lt;code>Windows Cloud Login&lt;/code>. This means you have to add this application to your CA policies. This can be done manually, but I prefer to automate this. In this blog post, I will show you how to add the &lt;code>Windows Cloud Login&lt;/code> application to your CA policies automated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Enable Endpoint Analytics automated in Microsoft Intune</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/enable-endpoint-analytics-automated-in-microsoft-endpoint-manager/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 10:23:17 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/enable-endpoint-analytics-automated-in-microsoft-endpoint-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>Happy users are key. But with all the changes in hardware, software distributions, security- and OS updates, it could take a lot of effort. Now remote working is embedded into our culture it costs even more effort to keep sight of what is happening. Endpoint analytics gives you insight into how the organization is working and the quality of experience which is delivered to users. I show how to enable endpoint analytics automated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The DevOps Project Clone a pipeline from a source project automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/the-devops-project-clone-a-pipeline-from-a-source-project-automated/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 20:41:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/the-devops-project-clone-a-pipeline-from-a-source-project-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this 4th slice of Prepare Azure DevOps for AVD deployment series, I will show how to copy or clone an existing YAML pipeline automated from a source project into a new AVD project. This will help you keep one main pipeline as a source and will allow you to create a “linked” pipeline into a new project directly from the source.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Secure and optimize AVD and CloudPC using Microsoft Intune</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/secure-and-optimize-avd-and-cloudpc-using-microsoft-endpoint-manager/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 12:39:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/secure-and-optimize-avd-and-cloudpc-using-microsoft-endpoint-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this blog post, I explain how to secure and optimize AVD and CloudPC environment using Microsoft Intune automated. The configuration is all deployed automated based on PowerShell, JSON templates, and Graph API. I explain how to create a security baseline and how to deploy a configuration profile with settings.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AVD Automation Cocktail – Deploy AVD AzureAD with DevOps and Az.Avd</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-deploy-avd-azuread-with-devops-and-az-avd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 10:16:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-deploy-avd-azuread-with-devops-and-az-avd/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the AVD Automation Cocktail. In this cocktail series, I will show different AVD deployment strategies and languages. In this cocktail, Santa’s Tree Ride, I will show you how to deploy an AzureAD joined only AVD environment automated with DevOps and the Az.Avd PowerShell module.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Configure FSLogix profile for Azure AD joined AVD session host automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/configure-fslogix-profile-for-azure-ad-joined-avd-session-host-automated/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 14:34:21 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/configure-fslogix-profile-for-azure-ad-joined-avd-session-host-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this blog post, I explain how to configure FSLogix for Azure AD-joined machines automated. Also, I explain how to test the configuration and I rearranged the installation procedure in a more efficient way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AVD Automation Cocktail – Deploy AVD with Terraform Cloud</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-terraform-cloud/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 10:41:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-terraform-cloud/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome (back) to the AVD Automation Cocktail. In the past &lt;a href="https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-the-menu"




 target="_blank"
 


>cocktail series&lt;/a>
, I showed different AVD deployment strategies and languages. During the time I got some requests about automation with Terraform. In this cocktail, The Dutch Bloody Harry, I’ll show you how to deploy an AVD environment automated with Terraform Cloud and Github. I’m using the Terraform cloud combined with my GitHub repository.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to enable AVD scaling plans automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/how-to-enable-avd-scaling-plans-automated/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 17:58:45 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/how-to-enable-avd-scaling-plans-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this article, I explain how to configure AVD scaling plans automated with the Az.Avd module. This is one of the options to save costs on AVD. A plan which helps you start VM’s when needed. And stopping VM’s when not needed. Microsoft announced the public preview of AVD auto-scaling.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Manage Windows Updates for AVD using Microsoft Intune</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/manage-windows-updates-for-avd-using-microsoft-endpoint-manager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 22:44:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/manage-windows-updates-for-avd-using-microsoft-endpoint-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this article, I explain a way how to manage Windows Updates for Azure Virtual Desktop (AVD). To achieve this goal I use update rings in Microsoft Intune. These update rings will be assigned to a dynamic Azure AD group. I also show how to create and assign this configuration automated with the use of PowerShell.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Manage AVD automated with Microsoft Intune</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/manage-avd-automated-with-microsoft-endpoint-manager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 14:11:01 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/manage-avd-automated-with-microsoft-endpoint-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to a brand new series called Operation North Star. In the upcoming series, I will show how to manage AVD environments with Microsoft Intune. I talk about how to manage AVD environments and how to deploy these settings automated. At last, I try to show how to configure a new way of management.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using VM templates for AVD sessionhost automation</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/using-vm-templates-for-avd-sessionhost-automation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 12:01:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/using-vm-templates-for-avd-sessionhost-automation/</guid><description>&lt;p>In automation using templates is key! Using templates makes life easier. No new information I guess. If you run tasks in DevOps, Terraform, or other engines you want to reuse code blocks. When deploying resources in Azure we use ARM or Bicep templates. Good to know there is also is a sort of ‘in place’-template available for AVD. This is the VM template and stored under the host pool information. In this blog post, I explain how to set and use VM templates. This will help you with the AVD sessionhost automation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to deal with AVD session hosts version management</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/how-to-deal-with-avd-session-hosts-version-management/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 12:20:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/how-to-deal-with-avd-session-hosts-version-management/</guid><description>&lt;p>A Shared Image Gallery is a great way to distribute images over multiple environments. This great feature is also its disadvantage. When using a Shared Image Gallery in combination with several environments with even more host pools you will lose sight fast. At this moment there is no good overview of which host in which environment is using which version.&lt;br>
In this article, I will explain how to deal with AVD session hosts and version management. This will help to keep your environment clean and save costs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Move AVD session hosts to a new host pool with REST API</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/move-avd-session-hosts-to-a-new-host-pool-with-rest-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 08:35:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/move-avd-session-hosts-to-a-new-host-pool-with-rest-api/</guid><description>&lt;p>Azure Virtual Desktop is growing and becomes available at new (metadata) locations more and more. In this article, I will explain how to move AVD session hosts to a new AVD host pool. metadata location with REST API and PowerShell.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to deploy Windows 11 in an AVD environment</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/how-to-deploy-windows-11-in-an-avd-environment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 12:36:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/how-to-deploy-windows-11-in-an-avd-environment/</guid><description>&lt;p>After the Windows 11 launch everyone was waiting till Windows 11 came available in Azure. Since the 19th of August Windows 11 became in preview. I decided to test it in a AVD environment. Because it is not a next-next-finish installation I will explain how to deploy Windows 11 in an AVD environment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to join Azure AD automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/how-to-join-azure-ad-automated/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 16:55:50 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/how-to-join-azure-ad-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this article, I show how to deploy and join an Azure VM to Azure AD join automated. In the deployment, I use two different ways of deployment. I use PowerShell and Azure CLI. Additionally, I show how to install the AVD extension with the Azure AD join.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AVD Automation Cocktail – AVD automated with Azure CLI</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-azure-cli/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 14:59:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-azure-cli/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the AVD Automation Cocktail. In this cocktail series I will show different AVD deployment strategies and languages. In this cocktail, the Sweet Orange Sunset, I will show you how to deploy an AVD environment automated with Azure CLI. Great new feature in this cocktail is the Azure AAD Join feature.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AVD Automation Cocktail - Azure Virtual Desktop automated with REST API</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-rest-api/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 16:10:50 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-rest-api/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the AVD Automation Cocktail. In this cocktail series, I will show different AVD deployment strategies and languages. In this cocktail, the Pineapple Citrus Splash, I will show you how to deploy an AVD environment automated with REST API, and JSON executed with PowerShell.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AVD Automation Cocktail - Azure Virtual Desktop automated with DevOps and ARM</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-devops-and-arm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 15:13:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-devops-and-arm/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the AVD Automation Cocktail. In this cocktail series I will show different AVD deployment strategies and languages. In this cocktail, the Strawberry Banana Mix, I will show you how to deploy an AVD environment automated with DevOps, ARM templates and a bit of PowerShell.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AVD Automation Cocktail - Azure Virtual Desktop automated with PowerShell</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 11:28:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the AVD Automation Cocktail. In this cocktail series, I will show different AVD deployment strategies and languages. In this cocktail, the Coconut Beach Party, I will show you how to deploy an AVD environment automated with PowerShell only.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AVD Automation Cocktail - Azure Virtual Desktop automated with Bicep and Azure CLI</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-with-bicep-and-azure-cli/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-with-bicep-and-azure-cli/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the updated AVD Automation Cocktail. This cocktail is updated with all new Bicep and AVD features since september 2023.
In this cocktail series I will show different AVD deployment strategies and languages. In this cocktail, the Fresh Minty Breeze, I will show you how to deploy an AVD environment automated with Bicep and Azure CLI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AVD Automation Cocktail - The Menu</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-the-menu/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 20:21:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-the-menu/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to a fresh new series about deploying Azure Virtual Desktop environments automated called the “AVD Automation Cocktail”. In this series I will serve several cocktails and will take you along on the AVD automated deployment journey with different types of automation languages. Every type has its own pros and cons, deployment strategy, parameter structure and commands. In the series all of these items will pass and hopefully it will give you a good overview about the possibilities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Change AVD disk size based on the Azure Compute Gallery image automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/change-avd-disk-size-based-on-a-shared-image-gallery-image-automated/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 11:10:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/change-avd-disk-size-based-on-a-shared-image-gallery-image-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>It is very common to use a golden image in Azure Virtual Desktop environments. Some are using Azure images, others are using a Shared Image Gallery. A great advantage of using preconfigured images is that you just have to create a new session host from that image and you’re all set.&lt;br>
The &lt;a href="https://www.rozemuller.com/create-avd-image-version-based-on-existing-config-with-powershell/"




 target="_blank"
 


>change process&lt;/a>
 for an image version is very simple, you will start a virtual machine from the version and you will make the changes. But what if you need to change the OS disk size of the golden image? In this article, I will explain how to change an Azure Virtual Desktop disk size when using a golden image based on the existing environment automated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Launching the first version of Az.Avd WVD PowerShell module</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/launching-the-first-version-of-az-avd-powershell-module/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 13:21:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/launching-the-first-version-of-az-avd-powershell-module/</guid><description>&lt;p>During my travel the past year in the world of AVD I noticed I’m using the common Az.DesktopVirtualization PowerShell module very often, but there are some limits. In basics they do their job but if you like more intelligence or add more resource types you will need to combine PowerShell commands to get useful information. That’s the point where I started writing a AVD PowerShell module and now it is time to share my functions as a fresh new module called Az.Avd.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Delete assigned user from a personal AVD session host automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/delete-assigned-user-from-a-personal-avd-session-host-automated/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 13:18:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/delete-assigned-user-from-a-personal-avd-session-host-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>An Azure Virtual Desktop environment has two types of host pools, a pooled and a personal type. The main difference between them is the user assignment. In this article I will show how to deal with personal assigned session hosts and how to delete the assigned user and will save work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Configure AVD Start VM on Connect automated with role assignments and Graph API</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/configure-avd-start-vm-on-connect-automated-with-role-assignments-and-graph-api/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 15:46:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/configure-avd-start-vm-on-connect-automated-with-role-assignments-and-graph-api/</guid><description>&lt;p>Costs are a topic of an Azure conversation very often. As we all know you pay for usage, if it is storage, CPU or bandwidth usage, (almost) every resource has its price. For Windows Virtual Desktop it means you have to pay for CPU usage, for example. It is important then to keep this usage as low as possible. Now there is an option to keep these usage as low as possible with AVD Start VM on Connect.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to configure dynamic recipients in DevOps environments</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/how-to-configure-dynamic-recipients-in-devops-environments/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 15:33:57 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/how-to-configure-dynamic-recipients-in-devops-environments/</guid><description>&lt;p>As mentioned in earlier posts Azure DevOps is a really nice way to deploy Azure resources automated. During my travel through Azure DevOps for managing Windows Virtual Desktop resources I moved from classic pipelines and releases to the new YAML pipelines. Using YAML has a lot of advantages in relation to classic. But there are some new challenges coming, approval or manual interventions for example. In this article I will explain how to use approvals and checks with dynamic recipients in DevOps environments within a YAML configuration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Configure Azure Firewall Premium features for AVD automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/configure-azure-firewall-premium-features-for-avd-automated/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 17:02:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/configure-azure-firewall-premium-features-for-avd-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>Security became important more and more. It is recommend, now the days arrived where the most people work from home and IT is moving to the public cloud, to use a good firewall with less complexity as possible. In case of AVD within the current situation an IT environment can be complex. In this article I will explain how configure an Azure Firewall for AVD automated with premium options, which came in public preview at 16 February 2021. At the end I will show how to deploy an Azure Firewall specially for a AVD environment with all the needed steps automated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using LaMetric Time to monitor an AVD environment</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/using-lametric-time-to-monitor-an-avd-environment/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 16:38:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/using-lametric-time-to-monitor-an-avd-environment/</guid><description>&lt;p>A lot of people in the Microsoft community are using a fancy gadget called LaMetric Time. It is a smart clock which can show time, receiving notifications from a lot of different environments and more. In this blog I will show how to use LaMetric Time to monitor a AVD environment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monitor Azure Virtual Desktop required URL&amp;#8217;s with Log Analytics Workspace</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/monitor-azure-virtual-desktop-required-urls-with-log-analytics-workspace/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 10:42:08 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/monitor-azure-virtual-desktop-required-urls-with-log-analytics-workspace/</guid><description>&lt;p>Microsoft has provided a list with URL’s which you need for running a Azure Virtual Desktop environment. In this blog post I will explain how to monitor any issues related to the AVD required URL’s. and how to setup the monitoring environment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prepare Azure DevOps for Azure Virtual Desktop deployment – Create DevOps project</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/prepare-azure-devops-for-azure-virtual-desktop-deployment-create-devops-project/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 16:02:21 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/prepare-azure-devops-for-azure-virtual-desktop-deployment-create-devops-project/</guid><description>&lt;p>An Azure DevOps environment consists of projects. Before create anything in DevOps like a board, repositories or pipelines you first need a project. In this second part of the series Prepare Azure DevOps for Azure Virtual Desktop we are diving into that DevOps part, a project. At the end of this post you will be able to deploy WVD with DevOps automated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploy Azure Monitor for AVD automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/deploy-azure-monitor-for-windows-virtual-desktop-automated/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 14:32:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/deploy-azure-monitor-for-windows-virtual-desktop-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>Monitoring user environments will help you get sight of what is going on and will help you solve problems. An Azure Virtual Desktop environment isn’t an exception. It is recommended to configure a monitoring environment. In this post, I will show how to deploy Azure Monitor for AVD fully automated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Azure Virtual Desktop Image Management Automated - Part 3 Create AVD sessionhosts on image version with ARM</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/create-avd-sessionhosts-based-on-shared-image-gallery-version-with-arm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 12:05:45 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/create-avd-sessionhosts-based-on-shared-image-gallery-version-with-arm/</guid><description>&lt;p>This article is serie of posts about AVD Image Management Automated. In this part we are going to add new sessionhosts to an existing AVD hostpool based on a ARM template.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Azure Virtual Desktop Image Management Automated - Part 2 Save AVD image with Sysprep as Image Gallery version</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/save-avd-image-with-sysprep-as-image-gallery-version/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 19:57:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/save-avd-image-with-sysprep-as-image-gallery-version/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is part two of a serie posts about AVD disk management. In this blogpost I will explain how to finish a disk with sysprep and deploy it as a version into the Azure Shared Image Gallery automated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AVD Image Management Automated - Part 1 Create an AVD image version based on the existing config with PowerShell</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/create-avd-image-version-based-on-existing-config-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 19:45:17 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/create-avd-image-version-based-on-existing-config-with-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p>This article is part one of a series of posts about AVD image management automated. In this first part, I will describe how to create and connect a new disk (based on a snapshot) to a new Azure VM based on the existing sessionhost configuration. This will save a lot of extra parameters like VM size, network settings, and type. After the VM is started you will get the information on how to connect to the VM by RDP (3389) with specific credentials specially created for this VM.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>