<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Azure on Sander Rozemuller | All about Identity, AVD, Automation, DevOps, Monitoring, Intune and Security</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/tags/azure/</link><description>Recent content in Azure on Sander Rozemuller | All about Identity, AVD, Automation, DevOps, Monitoring, Intune and Security</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 15:09:51 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.rozemuller.com/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Enable Azure Virtual Desktop Insights automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/enable-avd-insights-automated/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 01:28:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/enable-avd-insights-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>Azure Virtual Desktop (AVD) Insights is a way to get sight into your AVD environment. In short (from Microsoft), Azure Virtual Desktop Insights is a dashboard built on Azure Monitor Workbooks that helps IT professionals understand their Azure Virtual Desktop environments.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Route own Intune data to Log Analytics using custom logs</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/route-own-intune-data-to-log-analytics-using-custom-logs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 09:28:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/route-own-intune-data-to-log-analytics-using-custom-logs/</guid><description>&lt;p>I often write blogs about getting data with the Graph API and using it for monitoring. A while ago I was thinking about how to get my own data into Log Analytics.&lt;br>
In this blog post, I show how to ingest custom MEM data into a Log Analytics table. I also show how to configure all components in an automated way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Endpoint Security Train - Introduction</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/the-endpoint-security-train-introduction/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 07:38:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/the-endpoint-security-train-introduction/</guid><description>&lt;p>The IT landscape is changing. Private becomes public, local resources are moving to the public cloud. More and more workloads return to the local endpoint. Cloud endpoints (AVD, W365) are mostly used to run legacy software.
With all those movements, it could be challenging to keep the herd in the pasture. Devices are everywhere and what about security?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Disable user tenant creation</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/disable-user-tenant-creation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 20:38:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/disable-user-tenant-creation/</guid><description>&lt;p>It looks like Microsoft has added a new option that allows users to create tenants. Some people have seen the Tenant Creation option in the regular Azure portal but was removed fast. For now, the option is still available in the Preview Azure Portal (&lt;a href="https://preview.portal.azure.com/"




 target="_blank"
 


>https://preview.portal.azure.com/&lt;/a>
)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Route AVD traffic through static WAN IP with Azure Firewall automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/route-avd-traffic-static-wan-ip-with-azure-firewall-automated/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 07:55:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/route-avd-traffic-static-wan-ip-with-azure-firewall-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently I had a situation where a customer asked me how to make sure the AVD environment always has the same WAN IP. To give Azure Virtual Desktop a fixed external IP, some options are available. Think about a NAT gateway or an Azure Firewall. In this blog post, I show how to configure a static WAN IP for AVD with the use of the Azure Firewall in an automated way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Resize AVD session host via Azure Monitor Alerts</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/resize-avd-sessionhost-based-on-performance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 07:55:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/resize-avd-sessionhost-based-on-performance/</guid><description>&lt;details class="table-of-content">
 &lt;summary>Table Of Contents&lt;/summary>
 &lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#session-host-insights-via-azure-monitor">Session host insights via Azure Monitor&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#create-alert-rule-from-the-logs">Create alert rule from the logs&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#action-group-triggers-function-app">Action group triggers function app&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#function-app-that-resizes-the-session-host">Function app that resizes the session host&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;/details>

&lt;h2 id="session-host-insights-via-azure-monitor">Session host insights via Azure Monitor&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Enable insights creates a data collection rule under Azure Monitor Settings. This rule captures performance log data and sends the data to a log analytics workspace.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monitor and get alerts from Microsoft Intune</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/monitor-and-get-alerts-from-microsoft-endpoint-manager/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 11:14:54 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/monitor-and-get-alerts-from-microsoft-endpoint-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>Out of the box, Microsoft Intune has a reporting platform where lots of information is stored. Think about device management or endpoint analytics. For troubleshooting, reports can help. However, if you need to troubleshoot you are too late in the first place. It would be nice to get alerts out of Microsoft Intune. Luckily, there are options to achieve that goal. In this post, I show a way to monitor and get alerts from Microsoft Intune.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Azure file share usage monitoring with Logic Apps</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/azure-file-share-usage-monitoring-with-logic-apps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 21:14:53 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/azure-file-share-usage-monitoring-with-logic-apps/</guid><description>&lt;p>Earlier I explained how to use the REST API to get more information about Azure file shares. This is because we like to monitor file share usage based on absolute values. In this blog post, I explain the follow-up for Azure file share usage monitoring with Logic Apps. First I explain how the Logic App works and how I did the maths. Second I explain how to deploy this Logic App automated. In the end, we have a deployment of Azure file share usage monitoring in an automated way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monitor FSLogix file share usage on Azure Files</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/monitor-fslogix-file-share-usage-on-azure-files/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 07:44:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/monitor-fslogix-file-share-usage-on-azure-files/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the new world of (Azure) Virtual Desktops and CloudPC, FSLogix is often used for handling user profiles. Now FSLogix is supported with the back of AzureAD only, FSLogix is almost a required component in an AVD or CloudPC environment. With that in mind is it extremely important to know if the FSLogix file share has enough space. In this post, I explain how to monitor the FSLogix file share usage.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AVD Automation Cocktail – Deploy AVD AzureAD with DevOps and Az.Avd</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-deploy-avd-azuread-with-devops-and-az-avd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 10:16:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-deploy-avd-azuread-with-devops-and-az-avd/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the AVD Automation Cocktail. In this cocktail series, I will show different AVD deployment strategies and languages. In this cocktail, Santa’s Tree Ride, I will show you how to deploy an AzureAD joined only AVD environment automated with DevOps and the Az.Avd PowerShell module.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to enable AVD scaling plans automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/how-to-enable-avd-scaling-plans-automated/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 17:58:45 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/how-to-enable-avd-scaling-plans-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this article, I explain how to configure AVD scaling plans automated with the Az.Avd module. This is one of the options to save costs on AVD. A plan which helps you start VM’s when needed. And stopping VM’s when not needed. Microsoft announced the public preview of AVD auto-scaling.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to configure dynamic recipients in DevOps environments</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/how-to-configure-dynamic-recipients-in-devops-environments/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 15:33:57 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/how-to-configure-dynamic-recipients-in-devops-environments/</guid><description>&lt;p>As mentioned in earlier posts Azure DevOps is a really nice way to deploy Azure resources automated. During my travel through Azure DevOps for managing Windows Virtual Desktop resources I moved from classic pipelines and releases to the new YAML pipelines. Using YAML has a lot of advantages in relation to classic. But there are some new challenges coming, approval or manual interventions for example. In this article I will explain how to use approvals and checks with dynamic recipients in DevOps environments within a YAML configuration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploy Azure Monitor for AVD automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/deploy-azure-monitor-for-windows-virtual-desktop-automated/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 14:32:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/deploy-azure-monitor-for-windows-virtual-desktop-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>Monitoring user environments will help you get sight of what is going on and will help you solve problems. An Azure Virtual Desktop environment isn’t an exception. It is recommended to configure a monitoring environment. In this post, I will show how to deploy Azure Monitor for AVD fully automated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Azure Virtual Desktop Image Management Automated – Part 4 AVD Clean up unused resources</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-clean-up-unused-resources/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 20:08:27 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-clean-up-unused-resources/</guid><description>&lt;p>The current situation, we have created new disks, snapshots, virtual machines, networks, images and session hosts. All the resources has been added to the existing AVD hostpool. Now it is time to cleanup the old resources, to keep everything nice and clean. In this part we will take care of removing components related to the old image version.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Azure Virtual Desktop Image Management Automated - Part 2 Save AVD image with Sysprep as Image Gallery version</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/save-avd-image-with-sysprep-as-image-gallery-version/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 19:57:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/save-avd-image-with-sysprep-as-image-gallery-version/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is part two of a serie posts about AVD disk management. In this blogpost I will explain how to finish a disk with sysprep and deploy it as a version into the Azure Shared Image Gallery automated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monitor active M365 ServiceHealth services only with PowerShell</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/monitor-active-m365-servicehealth-services-only-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 11:55:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/monitor-active-m365-servicehealth-services-only-with-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p>You have some Microsoft 365 (M365) customers which you like to monitor. Every day you are looking at the customer specific M365 portal looking for Microsoft event.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AVD Image Management Automated - Part 1 Create an AVD image version based on the existing config with PowerShell</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/create-avd-image-version-based-on-existing-config-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 19:45:17 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/create-avd-image-version-based-on-existing-config-with-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p>This article is part one of a series of posts about AVD image management automated. In this first part, I will describe how to create and connect a new disk (based on a snapshot) to a new Azure VM based on the existing sessionhost configuration. This will save a lot of extra parameters like VM size, network settings, and type. After the VM is started you will get the information on how to connect to the VM by RDP (3389) with specific credentials specially created for this VM.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to use REST API with Powershell</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/how-to-use-rest-api-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 11:57:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/how-to-use-rest-api-with-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p>The past few years REST API became important more and more. REST API is a common way for communicating against and between applications. Azure and Microsoft 365 also using REST API’s.&lt;br>
As the world of API is growing so the tooling for querying API’s is growing with the most well known tool is &lt;a href="https://www.postman.com/"




 target="_blank"
 


>Postman&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>