<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Backup on Sander Rozemuller | All about Automation, Monitoring for Identity, AVD and Intune</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/backup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Backup on Sander Rozemuller | All about Automation, Monitoring for Identity, AVD and Intune</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 07:55:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/backup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Intune settings catalog automated from scratch with Graph API</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/deploy-intune-settings-catalog-automated-from-scratch-with-graph-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 07:55:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/deploy-intune-settings-catalog-automated-from-scratch-with-graph-api/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I show in this blog how to create a device configuration profile based on the settings catalog in Intune. A while ago I&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rozemuller.com/deploy-power-settings-automated-in-microsoft-endpoint-manager/&#34;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&#xA; &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&gt; created a profile with power settings and deployed the profile to all devices including a filter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automatically backup Azure resources to an Azure Storage Account in JSON</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/automatically-backup-azure-resources-to-an-azure-storage-account-in-json/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 08:04:04 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/automatically-backup-azure-resources-to-an-azure-storage-account-in-json/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this quick blog post I will explain a way how to backup Azure resources and how to restore them with PowerShell, in JSON format, to an Azure Storage Account which is “deployment ready”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disaster recovery plan for Azure Key Vault using tags, PowerShell and Azure Function</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/disaster-recovery-plan-for-azure-key-vault-using-tags-powershell-and-azure-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 05:37:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/disaster-recovery-plan-for-azure-key-vault-using-tags-powershell-and-azure-function/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By default the Azure Key Vault has softdelete enabled with a 90 day retention. This option will protect Key Vault items when deleted by accident. When deleted you are able to restore that item through the portal or PowerShell.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;But what if someone has deleted the Key Vault itself with all the items and softdeleted items included. There is no option to restore a Key Vault. In this article I will describe a way how to backup and restore a Key Vault when deleted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
