<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Disks on Sander Rozemuller | All about Identity, AVD, Automation, DevOps, Monitoring, Intune and Security</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/tags/disks/</link><description>Recent content in Disks on Sander Rozemuller | All about Identity, AVD, Automation, DevOps, Monitoring, Intune and Security</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 15:09:51 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.rozemuller.com/tags/disks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Change AVD disk size based on the Azure Compute Gallery image automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/change-avd-disk-size-based-on-a-shared-image-gallery-image-automated/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 11:10:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/change-avd-disk-size-based-on-a-shared-image-gallery-image-automated/</guid><description>&lt;p>It is very common to use a golden image in Azure Virtual Desktop environments. Some are using Azure images, others are using a Shared Image Gallery. A great advantage of using preconfigured images is that you just have to create a new session host from that image and you’re all set.&lt;br>
The &lt;a href="https://www.rozemuller.com/create-avd-image-version-based-on-existing-config-with-powershell/"




 target="_blank"
 


>change process&lt;/a>
 for an image version is very simple, you will start a virtual machine from the version and you will make the changes. But what if you need to change the OS disk size of the golden image? In this article, I will explain how to change an Azure Virtual Desktop disk size when using a golden image based on the existing environment automated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Azure Virtual Desktop Image Management Automated - Part 2 Save AVD image with Sysprep as Image Gallery version</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/save-avd-image-with-sysprep-as-image-gallery-version/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 19:57:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/save-avd-image-with-sysprep-as-image-gallery-version/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is part two of a serie posts about AVD disk management. In this blogpost I will explain how to finish a disk with sysprep and deploy it as a version into the Azure Shared Image Gallery automated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AVD Image Management Automated - Part 1 Create an AVD image version based on the existing config with PowerShell</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/create-avd-image-version-based-on-existing-config-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 19:45:17 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/create-avd-image-version-based-on-existing-config-with-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p>This article is part one of a series of posts about AVD image management automated. In this first part, I will describe how to create and connect a new disk (based on a snapshot) to a new Azure VM based on the existing sessionhost configuration. This will save a lot of extra parameters like VM size, network settings, and type. After the VM is started you will get the information on how to connect to the VM by RDP (3389) with specific credentials specially created for this VM.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>