<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure CLI on Sander Rozemuller | All about Automation, Monitoring for Identity, AVD and Intune</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/azure-cli/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure CLI on Sander Rozemuller | All about Automation, Monitoring for Identity, AVD and Intune</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 16:55:50 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/azure-cli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to join Azure AD  automated</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/how-to-join-azure-ad-automated/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 16:55:50 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/how-to-join-azure-ad-automated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this article, I show how to deploy and join an Azure VM to Azure AD join automated. In the deployment, I use two different ways of deployment. I use PowerShell and Azure CLI. Additionally, I show how to install the AVD extension with the Azure AD join.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AVD Automation Cocktail – AVD automated with Azure CLI</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-azure-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 14:59:39 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-azure-cli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the AVD Automation Cocktail. In this cocktail series I will show different AVD deployment strategies and languages. In this cocktail, the Sweet Orange Sunset, I will show you how to deploy an AVD environment automated with Azure CLI. Great new feature in this cocktail is the Azure AAD Join feature.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AVD Automation Cocktail - Azure Virtual Desktop automated with Bicep and Azure CLI</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-with-bicep-and-azure-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-with-bicep-and-azure-cli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the updated AVD Automation Cocktail. This cocktail is updated with all new Bicep and AVD features since september 2023.&#xA;In this cocktail series I will show different AVD deployment strategies and languages. In this cocktail, the Fresh Minty Breeze, I will show you how to deploy an AVD environment automated with Bicep and Azure CLI.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
