<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DevOps on Sander Rozemuller | All about Identity, AVD, Automation, DevOps, Monitoring, Intune and Security</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/tags/devops/</link><description>Recent content in DevOps on Sander Rozemuller | All about Identity, AVD, Automation, DevOps, Monitoring, Intune and Security</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 15:09:51 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.rozemuller.com/tags/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AVD Automation Cocktail – Deploy AVD AzureAD with DevOps and Az.Avd</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-deploy-avd-azuread-with-devops-and-az-avd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 10:16:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-deploy-avd-azuread-with-devops-and-az-avd/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the AVD Automation Cocktail. In this cocktail series, I will show different AVD deployment strategies and languages. In this cocktail, Santa’s Tree Ride, I will show you how to deploy an AzureAD joined only AVD environment automated with DevOps and the Az.Avd PowerShell module.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AVD Automation Cocktail - Azure Virtual Desktop automated with DevOps and ARM</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-devops-and-arm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 15:13:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-avd-automated-with-devops-and-arm/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the AVD Automation Cocktail. In this cocktail series I will show different AVD deployment strategies and languages. In this cocktail, the Strawberry Banana Mix, I will show you how to deploy an AVD environment automated with DevOps, ARM templates and a bit of PowerShell.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AVD Automation Cocktail - The Menu</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-the-menu/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 20:21:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/avd-automation-cocktail-the-menu/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to a fresh new series about deploying Azure Virtual Desktop environments automated called the “AVD Automation Cocktail”. In this series I will serve several cocktails and will take you along on the AVD automated deployment journey with different types of automation languages. Every type has its own pros and cons, deployment strategy, parameter structure and commands. In the series all of these items will pass and hopefully it will give you a good overview about the possibilities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prepare Azure DevOps for AVD deployment – Create a Service Connection Automated</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/prepare-azure-devops-for-avd-deployment-create-a-service-connection/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 11:28:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/prepare-azure-devops-for-avd-deployment-create-a-service-connection/</guid><description>&lt;p>Using Azure DevOps is a really nice way to deploy resources in Azure, so also for Windows Virtual Desktop. Before you are able to deploy resources into Azure with pipelines you will need to setup a project and a service connection first. In post I will explain how to create a DevOps Service Connection the automated way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prepare Azure DevOps for Azure Virtual Desktop deployment – Create DevOps project</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/prepare-azure-devops-for-azure-virtual-desktop-deployment-create-devops-project/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 16:02:21 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/prepare-azure-devops-for-azure-virtual-desktop-deployment-create-devops-project/</guid><description>&lt;p>An Azure DevOps environment consists of projects. Before create anything in DevOps like a board, repositories or pipelines you first need a project. In this second part of the series Prepare Azure DevOps for Azure Virtual Desktop we are diving into that DevOps part, a project. At the end of this post you will be able to deploy WVD with DevOps automated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prepare Azure DevOps for Azure Virtual Desktop deployment - App registration</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/prepare-azure-devops-for-windows-virtual-desktop-deployment-app-registration/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 10:40:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/prepare-azure-devops-for-windows-virtual-desktop-deployment-app-registration/</guid><description>&lt;p>Using Azure DevOps is a really nice way to deploy resources in Azure, so also for Azure Virtual Desktop. Before you are able to deploy resources into Azure with pipelines you will need to setup a project and a service connection first. While configuring a service connection you will be asked for some specific tenant details.&lt;br>
In this short series I will explain every step you need to prepare DevOps for AVD deployment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using KeyVault certificates in Azure DevOps</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/using-keyvault-certificates-in-azure-devops/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 10:07:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/using-keyvault-certificates-in-azure-devops/</guid><description>&lt;p>Azure KeyVault is the security key management system in Azure where you can store keys, secrets and certificates. From that place you can use the items everywhere you like.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>