<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Azure API on Sander Rozemuller | All about Identity, AVD, Automation, DevOps, Monitoring, Intune and Security</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/tags/azure-api/</link><description>Recent content in Azure API on Sander Rozemuller | All about Identity, AVD, Automation, DevOps, Monitoring, Intune and Security</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 18:41:23 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.rozemuller.com/tags/azure-api/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Schedule image update Azure Virtual Desktop host pool</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/blog/2024-02-20-schedule-image-update-avd-hostpool/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 01:28:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/blog/2024-02-20-schedule-image-update-avd-hostpool/</guid><description>&lt;p>When you want to update session hosts in a host pool with automated management, you use session host update. Session host update enables you to update the underlying virtual machine (VM) image, size, disk type, and other configuration properties. It does this by deleting or deallocating the existing virtual machine and creating a new one with the updated configuration stored in the session host configuration.
I&amp;rsquo;m realy exited abou this new feature.
In this blog, I explain this new feature in how it works, where to think of when using it and, how to manage this (in an automated way).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Find specific Azure Virutal Desktop assigned user</title><link>https://www.rozemuller.com/find-azure-virtual-desktop-assigned-user/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 16:44:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.rozemuller.com/find-azure-virtual-desktop-assigned-user/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently I saw a question on X (Twitter) where someone was looking for a way to filter for a specific Azure Virtual Desktop assigned user using the Azure management API. For some reason, the filter option is not working in this API. Where in the end it was not possible to find the correct user directly from an API request.
In this post, I show a different, also more efficient way, to find the correct user assigned to an Azure Virtual Desktop session host.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>